A Guide to the B. P. Blasingame Papers, c.1962-1978
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
B. P. Blasingame Papers, c.1962-1978
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1987-010
0.8 cu. ft. 2 boxes
The B. P. Blasingame Papers contains several books, reports, and papers about navigation, inertia, and space flight. Although the majority of the materials are undated, they are likely from the 1960s and 1970s.
Blasingame, B. P., (Benjamin Paul), 1919-
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The B. P. Blasingame Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1987.
Biographical Note
Dr. Benjamin Paul Blasingame was born on August 1, 1919 in State College, Pennsylvania. He majored in mechanical engineering at Pennsylvania State College and was a cadet in the school's ROTC program. He graduated in 1940 and was called to active duty in the United States Air Force in 1941. While still in the Air Force, Blasingame received his Doctor of Science degree in 1950 from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. After his military career, Blasingame became the director of engineering at AC Spark Plug, the Electronics Division (Delco) of General Motors. Under his leadership Delco would become the leading contractor for NASA's Apollo guidance and navigation systems.
For a more complete biographical sketch of Dr. Blasingame see: http://www.afspc.af.mil/shared/media/document/AFD-100405-043.pdf
Scope and Content
The B. P. Blasingame Papers contains several books, reports, and papers about navigation, inertia, and space flight. Although the majority of the materials are undated, they are likely from the 1960s and 1970s. Series I: Books and Record Albums includes three books related to the Skylab I-IV space projects, five books related to the Apollo 12, 14, 16, 17, and Apollo-Soyuz missions, and one guide to orbital flight, as well as two copies of the CBS production "Man on the Moon," narrated by Walter Cronkite. Series II: Papers and Reports consists of four official reports by Charles Stark Draper, of Charles Stark Draper Laboratory, Inc., regarding inertial guidance and navigation. There is also a report on the optical tracking of the Apollo 12 spacecraft, published by the Manned Spacecraft Center, and an unpublished report on inertial systems by Dr. Blasingame in this series.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series by material type.
Index Terms
Persons:
Blasingame, B. P., (Benjamin Paul), 1919-; Draper, C. S., (Charles Stark), 1901-1987
Subjects:
Apollo 12 (Spacecraft); Apollo 14 (Spacecraft); Apollo 16 (Spacecraft); Apollo 17 (Spacecraft); Apollo Soyuz Test Project; Archives of American Aerospace Exploration (AAAE); Science and Technology; Skylab Program
Contents List
- Series I: Books and Record Albums
  - "Man on the Moon" record albums, Produced by CBS News and narrated by Walter Cronkite. (2 copies) (Box 1)
  - Skylab I & 2 Program Description, published by Delco Electronics. (Box 1)
  - Skylab III Program Description, published by Delco Electronics. (Box 1)
  - Skylab IV Program Description, published by Delco Electronics. (Box 1)
  - Apollo 12 Guidance and Navigation Summary, published by AC Electronics. (Box 1)
  - Design Guide to Orbital Flight by Jorgen Jensen, George E. Townsend Jr., John D. Kraft, Jyri Kork. Published by McGraw Hill Book Company. A letter from Carl Kober, of the Martin Company, to Dr. Blaisingame., 1962 (Box 1)
  - Apollo 14 Guidance and Navigation Summary, published by Delco Electronics. (Box 2)
  - Apollo 16 Guidance and Navigation Summary, published by Delco Electronics. (Box 2)
  - Apollo 17 Guidance and Navigation Summary, published by Delco Electronics. (Box 2)
  - Apollo-Soyuz Project (ASTP) Program Description, published by Delco Electronics. (Box 2)
- Series II: Papers and Reports
  - Reliability Achievement in Inertial Systems by B. P. Blasingame, unpublished, 1973 (Box 2)
  - NASA Report, Optical Tracking of the Apollo 12 Spacecraft, Manned Spacecraft Center, Houston, TX, February 17, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Report P-727 The Future of Inertial Navigation by Charles Stark Draper, October 1978 (Box 2)
  - Report R-1185 Inertial Guidance, Basic Geometrical Theory, Sensor Technology, and Subsystem Functioning by Charles Stark Draper, August 1978 (Box 2)
  - Report R-923 Engineering Design Features of Sensors for Realizing Ultimately Useful Performance from Systems to Serve the Purposes of Geometrical Stabilization, Control, Tracking, and Guidance (U) by Charles Stark Draper,December 1975 (Box 2)
  - Report R-886 Ultimately Useful Guidance and Geometrical Indication (U) by Charles Stark Draper, June 1975 (Box 2)